

PATRICK KIMANJE

Phone: +256 750461002

Address: Kampala - Uganda

E-mail: dr.kimanjepatrick@gmail.com

Website: https://drkimpatrick2.netlify.com

FULL-STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

PROFILE

Hi! My name is Kimanje Patrick. Am a full-stack self taught software developer. I have 2+ years of professional software development experience. I have been developing in the following technologies. HTML, CSS, JavaScript(ES6+), Reactjs, Redux, bootstrap, materialize, Python (Django and Flask), Node.js/Express, MongoDB, PostgreSQL and Typescript. I also exercise unit testing and use continuous integration tools. Am a true team player with vast knowledge on how to work in teams. Seeking the opportunity to provide outstanding, clean code in a collaborative environment. An excellent communicator with the ability to meet deadlines and quickly resolve issues.

EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

A23labs (2017 - 2018)

- Wrote clean, clear and well-tested code for various projects in Node js/Express/Mongodb/Flask.
- Built, tested and deployed scalable, highly available and modular software products.
- Collaborated on all stages of the systems development lifecycle, from requirements gathering to production releases.
- Created a USSD application integrated with Africa's talking in python flask
- Developed the frontend of the EasyDial app in React JS and styled-components

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Andela (2018 - 2019)

- Collaborated with other developers to identify and alleviate the number of bugs in the software.
- Wrote clean, clear and well-tested code for various projects in Python/JavaScript (React).
- Developed Authors Haven using Python Django and React.js.
- Designed React application components.
- Presented project progress and updates to the team and TTL at key points in development.
- Wrote and implemented scripts to enhance the user experience

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Cognative insights (2019 - Present)

- Created the backend API for the Unclebob app which connects clients to service providers. The Unclebob app has three sections the admin portal, client mobile app and the artisan app which all use the same API. Unclebob was written in Node/Express and used MongoDB && ReactNative.
- Built and deployed application on AWS.
- Used docker for containerization.
- Developed object-oriented software, including Unclebob.

SKILLS

- Node js/Express/Mongodb
- Javascript Es6+
- Docker
- CI/CD/Git
- Python, Flask & Django
- React / Redux
- PostgreSQL

- Typescript
- Rest APIs
- Cloud computing
- Bootstrap/Materialize
- Unit-testing
- AWS
- Html && css

EDUCATION

UDACITY

Cloud computing (2019 - Present) JavaScript(Es6+)

MONGODB UNIVERSITY

Aggregation framework (2019 - Present) Mongodb basics

UDFMY

Various Courses

GOOGLE AFRICA SCHOLARSHIP Mobile web specialist (2018)

ST.KIZITO SS KABOWA

High School Diploma, science, Oct. 2015

SOCIAL LINKS

GITHUB https://github.com/DrKimpatrick

LINKEDIN https://www.linkedin.com/in/drkimpatrick

PORTFOLIO https://drkimpatrick.netlify.com/

CODERSRANK https://profile.codersrank.io/user/drkimpatrick/asOthersSee